<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.cutwire.Prism</id>
  <name>Prism</name>
  <summary>Trigger and mix live visuals</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Prism is a beginner-friendly live visuals app for triggering clips and compositing
      overlays in real time. Made for school events, small concerts, and sports, it combines
      instant clip triggering with hands-on control of the program output.
    </p>
    <p>
      Instead of a fixed grid, clips live on a node-based canvas with groups, transform
      contexts, and audio routing — click to trigger, with no scenes or playlists to manage.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li
            >Node-based clip canvas with groups, transform contexts, audio routing, and a VJ hotkey grid</li>
      <li
            >Many source types: video, images, slideshows, webcams, screen and window capture, GLSL shaders, HTML/QML overlays, text, Lua scripts, NDI inputs, and phone cameras over WebRTC</li>
      <li>Live A/B deck mixing with a crossfader and per-deck speed control</li>
      <li
            >Per-clip trim, crop, transform, and composited text/image overlay editing</li>
      <li
            >Audio spectrum analysis driving shader inputs, plus master audio routing</li>
      <li>Reusable asset library with drag-and-drop onto the clip canvas</li>
      <li
            >Program output hub: mirror windows, optional NDI output, virtual-camera output, and program video/audio recording</li>
      <li
            >Panic controls: instant blackout, freeze-frame hold, and stay-tuned overlay</li>
      <li>OBS WebSocket integration and network remote control</li>
      <li>Session save and load with autosave and smart asset relinking</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#ccaff5</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#3c1c6e</color>
  </branding>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.cutwire.Prism.desktop</launchable>
  <developer id="org.cutwire">
    <name>CutWire Studios</name>
  </developer>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <categories>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
    <category>Video</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="homepage">https://cutwire.org/prism</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.cutwire.org/prism</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default" xml:lang="en">
      <image
            >https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/main/docs/screenshots/main-window.png</image>
      <caption
            >The main window with asset library, node graph canvas, and control panel</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image
            >https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/main/docs/screenshots/node-editor.png</image>
      <caption
            >Wiring inputs, effects, and outputs on the node graph canvas</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image
            >https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/main/docs/screenshots/input-types.png</image>
      <caption>Choosing from many supported media source types</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image
            >https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/main/docs/screenshots/video-effects.png</image>
      <caption>Applying live video effects in a process node</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image
            >https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/main/docs/screenshots/text-overlays.png</image>
      <caption>Compositing animated text overlays onto a source</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image
            >https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/main/docs/screenshots/overlay-editor.png</image>
      <caption>Editing composited text and image overlays</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image
            >https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/main/docs/screenshots/html-editor.png</image>
      <caption
            >Designing dynamic HTML overlays in the built-in visual editor</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image
            >https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CutWire-Studios/Prism/main/docs/screenshots/lua-scripting.png</image>
      <caption
            >Generating live overlays with the embedded Lua scripting runtime</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.2" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p
                >This release brings GPU-accelerated layer composition, a wider set of audio and
                shader tools, and Windows platform fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Layer composition now runs on the GPU, with smoother scrubbing and playback</li>
          <li
                    >New audio capture node, enhanced audio analysis, and more FFT-driven shader
                    types including particle terrain and wave curtain</li>
          <li>Improved process nodes, script node experience, and node menu</li>
          <li>Windows audio capture support and fixes for platform-specific launch issues</li>
          <li
                    >Fixed shader decay after audio pause and sources not refreshing after edits</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.1" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p
                >This release adds an audio effect chain, and several audio and platform fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li
                    >Audio effect chain support with a redesigned dial-based effect UI</li>
          <li
                    >Fixed a Flatpak sandbox permission issue by prompting for a recording save directory</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2025-06-17">
      <description>
        <p
                >First public release. Trigger clips from a node-based canvas, mix two decks with a crossfader, composite text and image overlays, and send the program out over NDI, a virtual camera, or a recording.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
